<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts - Copies on Sangeeth&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/posts---copy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts - Copies on Sangeeth&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 23:05:17 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts---copy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sharpen an Axe for Longer</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/posts---copy/sharpen-an-axe-for-longer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 23:05:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/posts---copy/sharpen-an-axe-for-longer/</guid>
      <description>The title is paraphrased from a quote that is incorrectly attributed to Abraham Lincoln:&#xA;To Cut Down a Tree in Five Minutes Spend Three Minutes Sharpening Your Axe&#xA;Anyway, what I think the quote is trying to say is, it&amp;rsquo;s okay for things to take time. That is, if you&amp;rsquo;re actively working on making the end result much better.&#xA;Since I am a world renowned champion of doing things the easy way™ but also doing things good enough™, I have found that the only reliable method for both those phrases to be true is if I take time to understand/study/figure out what the problem is 1.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The title is paraphrased from a quote that is <a href="https://quoteinvestigator.com/2014/03/29/sharp-axe/"><em>incorrectly</em></a> attributed to Abraham Lincoln:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>To Cut Down a Tree in Five Minutes Spend Three Minutes Sharpening Your Axe</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Anyway, what I think the quote is trying to say is, it&rsquo;s okay for things to take time. That is, if you&rsquo;re actively working on making the end result much better.</p>
<p>Since I am a world renowned champion of doing things <em>the easy way™</em> but also <em>doing things good enough™</em>, I have found that the only reliable method for both those phrases to be true is if I take time to understand/study/figure out what the problem is <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.</p>
<h3 id="case-study-for-this-case-to-study-supworking-titlesup">Case study for this case to study <!-- raw HTML omitted --><em>(working title)</em><!-- raw HTML omitted --></h3>
<p>This site for instance. I want to document my writings/thoughts but do not want to spend too much time in fixing the content for each post. My initial solution involved writing in markdown first, converting this to html (via a converter) and then using templates to ensure the header and footer elements were standardised from page to page. This caused a certain amount of friction and meant I spent much less time writing and more time doing admin <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup>.</p>
<p>I also wanted a landing page to act as a place to direct people to first that needed to have a different style from the posts page. Also since I had this need to keep everything as small as possible, I decided to write the HTML and CSS from scratch and use next to no JavaScript. his was okay, since I had a snappy page, but any time I made a change or decided to incorporate or test something new, something inevitably broke <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup>.</p>
<h3 id="the-fix">The fix</h3>
<p>Just use a CSS framework for the landing site and a static site generator geared to blogs for the posts page.</p>
<p>In my case this would be TailwindCSS and Hugo + Papermod. I could have saved a ton of headache earlier, by just spending some time with the really well written documentation online. I was being extra lazy and thought writing from scratch would be easier than learning something new <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">4</a></sup>.</p>
<h3 id="the-exception-that-proves-the-rule">The exception that proves the rule</h3>
<p>If you are a serial procrastinator, perhaps avoid doing this. You might end up sharpening your axe for much longer than necessary.</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h4 id="misc">MISC</h4>
<p>For more information on how to get a hugo blog started up with a custom theme (specifically for cloudflare pages and github), <a href="https://www.andrewhoog.com/post/git-submodule-for-hugo-themes/">this article</a> is super helpful</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>This mostly rings true, but there are times when it is better to start doing and stop studying&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>This is also known in certain circles as the devil&rsquo;s busywork <sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">5</a></sup>&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Mostly since I would forget the duct tape code I had used to duct tape other code.&#160;<a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:4">
<p>Don&rsquo;t write from scratch if you can avoid it guys. Avoid <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Not_invented_here">NIH syndrome</a>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:4" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:5">
<p>The circle I mention is currently one person as of the writing of this post, i.e. myself.&#160;<a href="#fnref:5" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
